<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://clareaulab.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://clareaulab.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2026-01-01T23:19:59+00:00</updated><id>https://clareaulab.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lareau Lab</title><subtitle>The Lareau Laboratory for Computational and Systems Immunology is in the csBio Program at Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center, New York, NY.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">First protein design paper online!    </title><link href="https://clareaulab.com/2025/12/13/protein-design.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First protein design paper online!    " /><published>2025-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2026-01-01T23:18:36+00:00</updated><id>https://clareaulab.com/2025/12/13/protein-design</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://clareaulab.com/2025/12/13/protein-design.html"><![CDATA[<p>The lab’s first paper on <em>de novo</em> protein design is <a href="https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.64898/2025.12.12.694033v1">out on bioRxiv</a>.
We screened over 1,500 new proteins for efficacy in binding and CAR T efficacy, discovering
principles that inform how to make effective CAR T cells for a variety of surface antigens. 
Congrats to Arthur, Hoyin, Betty, Benan, Abi, and Laura for leading the lab in a new direction!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The lab’s first paper on de novo protein design is out on bioRxiv. We screened over 1,500 new proteins for efficacy in binding and CAR T efficacy, discovering principles that inform how to make effective CAR T cells for a variety of surface antigens. Congrats to Arthur, Hoyin, Betty, Benan, Abi, and Laura for leading the lab in a new direction!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New papers online!    </title><link href="https://clareaulab.com/2025/11/07/NewPapers2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New papers online!    " /><published>2025-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2026-01-01T23:18:36+00:00</updated><id>https://clareaulab.com/2025/11/07/NewPapers2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://clareaulab.com/2025/11/07/NewPapers2.html"><![CDATA[<p>Several papers from our collaborative projects are now online! Led by the Alex Gitlin lab,
<a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-025-09815-0">new work</a>
provides a thorough mechanistic characterization of VEXAS Syndrome.
In a shared effort with Payam Gammage and Ed Reznik, we help characterize functionally dominant 
hotspot mutations in <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41588-025-02374-0">mitochondrial ribosomal RNA</a>.
Finally, in a collaboration with Robbie Majzner’s group at Dana Farber, 
we defined how <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s43018-025-01056-4">SLP-76 can be engineered to improve T cell fitness and antigen sensitivity</a>.
Thanks to Benan and Hoyin for helping with these collaborative efforts!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Several papers from our collaborative projects are now online! Led by the Alex Gitlin lab, new work provides a thorough mechanistic characterization of VEXAS Syndrome. In a shared effort with Payam Gammage and Ed Reznik, we help characterize functionally dominant hotspot mutations in mitochondrial ribosomal RNA. Finally, in a collaboration with Robbie Majzner’s group at Dana Farber, we defined how SLP-76 can be engineered to improve T cell fitness and antigen sensitivity. Thanks to Benan and Hoyin for helping with these collaborative efforts!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">NYC Marathon!    </title><link href="https://clareaulab.com/2025/11/02/Marathon.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NYC Marathon!    " /><published>2025-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2026-01-01T23:18:36+00:00</updated><id>https://clareaulab.com/2025/11/02/Marathon</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://clareaulab.com/2025/11/02/Marathon.html"><![CDATA[<p>Cole and Caleb complete the <a href="https://www.nyrr.org/tcsnycmarathon">New York City Marathon</a>!
<a href="https://bsky.app/profile/caleblareau.bsky.social/post/3m4qegjaqlc2q">Thanks to the lab for coming out in support</a>
and for the generous donations <a href="https://secure2.convio.net/mskcc/site/TR?pg=personal&amp;fr_id=4272&amp;px=5441347">to Fred’s Team</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Cole and Caleb complete the New York City Marathon! Thanks to the lab for coming out in support and for the generous donations to Fred’s Team.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">National Academy of Medicine Catalyst    </title><link href="https://clareaulab.com/2025/10/01/NAMCatalyst.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="National Academy of Medicine Catalyst    " /><published>2025-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2026-01-01T23:18:36+00:00</updated><id>https://clareaulab.com/2025/10/01/NAMCatalyst</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://clareaulab.com/2025/10/01/NAMCatalyst.html"><![CDATA[<p>The lab is awarded a <a href="https://nam.edu/news-and-insights/2025-catalyst-awards-announcement/">Catalyst prize from the National Academy of Medicine</a>
for our continued work in defining the human virome. Thank you NAM for believing in our vision and supporting our work!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The lab is awarded a Catalyst prize from the National Academy of Medicine for our continued work in defining the human virome. Thank you NAM for believing in our vision and supporting our work!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Revised Logan Preprint    </title><link href="https://clareaulab.com/2025/09/01/Logan.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Revised Logan Preprint    " /><published>2025-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2026-01-01T23:18:36+00:00</updated><id>https://clareaulab.com/2025/09/01/Logan</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://clareaulab.com/2025/09/01/Logan.html"><![CDATA[<p>The lab collaborates in the latest generation of the <a href="https://github.com/IndexThePlanet/Logan">Logan Project</a>,
including a <a href="https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2024.07.30.605881v2">heavily revised preprint</a>.
Try it out for yourself using the <a href="https://logan-search.org/">LoganSearch webtool</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The lab collaborates in the latest generation of the Logan Project, including a heavily revised preprint. Try it out for yourself using the LoganSearch webtool.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New grant support!    </title><link href="https://clareaulab.com/2025/08/21/NOA.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New grant support!    " /><published>2025-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2026-01-01T23:18:36+00:00</updated><id>https://clareaulab.com/2025/08/21/NOA</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://clareaulab.com/2025/08/21/NOA.html"><![CDATA[<p>The lab receives an Notice of Award from the National Cancer Institute’s 
<a href="https://www.cancer.gov/about-nci/organization/cssi/research/imat">IMAT Program</a>
for advanced development of nucleic acid cytometry!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The lab receives an Notice of Award from the National Cancer Institute’s IMAT Program for advanced development of nucleic acid cytometry!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">100 mile run!    </title><link href="https://clareaulab.com/2025/08/03/Ultra.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="100 mile run!    " /><published>2025-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2026-01-01T23:18:36+00:00</updated><id>https://clareaulab.com/2025/08/03/Ultra</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://clareaulab.com/2025/08/03/Ultra.html"><![CDATA[<p>Paul, Cole and Caleb conquer the <a href="https://www.tenjunkmilesracing.com/badger-100-mile">Badger 101.1 mile trail race</a>!
Check out these <a href="https://bsky.app/profile/caleblareau.bsky.social/post/3lvnnedm77s2m">exhausted but ecstatic finishers!!</a>.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Paul, Cole and Caleb conquer the Badger 101.1 mile trail race! Check out these exhausted but ecstatic finishers!!.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New papers online!    </title><link href="https://clareaulab.com/2025/07/25/NewPapers.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New papers online!    " /><published>2025-07-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2026-01-01T23:18:36+00:00</updated><id>https://clareaulab.com/2025/07/25/NewPapers</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://clareaulab.com/2025/07/25/NewPapers.html"><![CDATA[<p>A flurry of papers are now out this month! Out now in PNAS, our characterization 
of purifying selection in a <a href="https://www.pnas.org/doi/10.1073/pnas.2505704122">mtDNA synonymous allele</a>
is published. Check out the <a href="https://x.com/Satpathology/status/1948547980883099905">fun backstory here</a>. 
Next, a preprint with the <a href="https://www.dhindsalab.com/">Dhindsa Lab @BCM</a> studying 
Epstein-Barr virus using population sequencing is <a href="https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2025.07.18.665549v1">out on bioRxiv</a>.
Finally, a collaboration with the Satpathy lab is available
<a href="https://www.biorxiv.org/content/10.1101/2025.07.16.665245v1">on bioRxiv now!</a>
Congratulations to Sherry, Erin, Jacob, Benan, Meghana, Thahmina, and Laura for their huge
contributions to these works spanning mitochondrial genetics, cancer biology, and viral persistence!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A flurry of papers are now out this month! Out now in PNAS, our characterization of purifying selection in a mtDNA synonymous allele is published. Check out the fun backstory here. Next, a preprint with the Dhindsa Lab @BCM studying Epstein-Barr virus using population sequencing is out on bioRxiv. Finally, a collaboration with the Satpathy lab is available on bioRxiv now! Congratulations to Sherry, Erin, Jacob, Benan, Meghana, Thahmina, and Laura for their huge contributions to these works spanning mitochondrial genetics, cancer biology, and viral persistence!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cornell Protein Science Symposium!    </title><link href="https://clareaulab.com/2025/06/11/LauraProtein.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cornell Protein Science Symposium!    " /><published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2026-01-01T23:18:36+00:00</updated><id>https://clareaulab.com/2025/06/11/LauraProtein</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://clareaulab.com/2025/06/11/LauraProtein.html"><![CDATA[<p>Many members of the lab travel to Cornell @ Ithaca for the
<a href="https://proteomics.cornell.edu/events/protein-science-symposium/">Protein Science Symposium</a>! 
Congratulations to Laura for being selected to give a talk on exciting new
proteo-genomics work coming from the lab!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Many members of the lab travel to Cornell @ Ithaca for the Protein Science Symposium! Congratulations to Laura for being selected to give a talk on exciting new proteo-genomics work coming from the lab!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">High school STEM night!    </title><link href="https://clareaulab.com/2025/05/23/STEM.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="High school STEM night!    " /><published>2025-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2026-01-01T23:18:36+00:00</updated><id>https://clareaulab.com/2025/05/23/STEM</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://clareaulab.com/2025/05/23/STEM.html"><![CDATA[<p>The lab attends the NYSCI Teen &amp; STEM night!
Located at the New York Hall of Science, the 
<a href="https://nysci.org/stem-career-events">STEM career night</a> brought in &gt;500 local 
high school students to learn more about careers in science, technology, engineering, and 
mathematics. Our lab represented MSKCC, and our team shared about how AI enables 
new careers and potentially new cancer therapies! Thanks to Betty, Arthur, 
Benan, Zeyu, and Hoyin for spending their Friday night with a bunch of high schoolers!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The lab attends the NYSCI Teen &amp; STEM night! Located at the New York Hall of Science, the STEM career night brought in &gt;500 local high school students to learn more about careers in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics. Our lab represented MSKCC, and our team shared about how AI enables new careers and potentially new cancer therapies! Thanks to Betty, Arthur, Benan, Zeyu, and Hoyin for spending their Friday night with a bunch of high schoolers!]]></summary></entry></feed>